1700 years to build. 5500 miles long. What were they trying to keep out?
The Great Wall is a action, adventure, fantasy film directed by Zhang Yimou.
European mercenaries searching for black powder become embroiled in the defense of
the Great Wall of China against a horde of monstrous creatures.
William, played by Matt Damon.
Commander Lin Mae, played by Jing Tian.
Ballard, played by Willem Dafoe.
Strategist Wang, played by Andy Lau.
Tovar, played by Pedro Pascal.
General Shao, played by Zhang Hanyu.
The Great Wall (simplified Chinese: 长城; traditional Chinese: 長城) is a 2016 monster film directed by Zhang Yimou, with a
screenplay by Carlo Bernard, Doug Miro and Tony Gilroy, from a story by Max Brooks, Edward Zwick and Marshall Herskovitz.
An American and Chinese co-production starring Matt Damon, Jing Tian, Pedro Pascal, Willem Dafoe, and Andy Lau, the plot centers on two European mercenary warriors (Damon and Pascal)
imprisoned by imperial Chinese forces within the Great Wall of China after arriving in search of gunpowder, eventually joining forces with the Chinese to help combat an alien threat.
The Great Wall is Zhang's first English-language film.
Principal photography for the film began on March 30, 2015, in Qingdao,
China, and it premiered in Beijing on December 6, 2016.
It was released by China Film Group in China on December 16, 2016, the United States on February
17, 2017, by Universal Pictures, and in Japan on April 14, 2017, by Toho-Towa.
The film, which received mixed reviews from critics, grossed $334.9 million worldwide
and was considered a box-office bomb for losing up to $75 million.
The film explores themes of monster, china, archer,
female soldier, historical fiction.